Łukasz Olender | CV

ul. ks. Czempiela 21/6, 41-506 Chorzów, Poland

🛘 +48 509 524 115 🔹 🖂 lukiasz@gmail.com 🔹 🚱 github.com/lukiasz

I'm a .NET programmer with experience in leading a team. Passionate about every aspect of software development, with strong technical and business analysis skills. Being easy-going and motivated by achievements person, makes me constantly look for new opportunities – both in programming world and other parts of life.

Career

AC Project GmbH / Shiji Poland

AC Project System

Team Leader

November 2017-Now

I've taken an official role of leading a team. The team grew from 4 to 11 individuals during the last two years. From the technical perspective, I'm responsible for a few services including design decisions, code reviews, and development of some of the complex features such as:

- scripting solution on top of CQRS service layer,
- core of performance-critical searcher,
- heuristic-based solution for NP-hard scheduling problem.

AC Project GmbH

AC Project System

Lead Programmer

Febuary 2016-November 2017

I was developing a distributed hotel management software. Being inside the company from its beginning, I've had an opportunity to write such a big project from scratch. I was involved in almost every aspect of the project, including:

- developing microservices-oriented architecture from scratch as a member of the core team,
- analyzing business needs, designing and developing business functionalities as a leader of a team of four,
- doing technical interviews with new developers coming into a company.

Keywords: C#, .NET Core, Domain Driven Design, Elastic Search, PostgreSQL, Microservices, CQRS, Web API.

LGBS Polska Sp. z o.o.

RezNext: Real-Time Hotel Distribution Management

Technical Consultant, C# Programmer

April 2015-Febuary 2016

I was designing and partially developing a new architecture of distributed hotel management software as a technical consultant working for a Reznext Global Solutions Pvt Ltd. Headquarters of Reznext are located in Bangalore, India and most of my work I was doing remotely. Technology stack: C#, .NET, Windows Azure, SQL Server. Things accomplished:

- designed efficient and reliable architecture solutions for main bottlenecks in the existing system,
- implemented some of the critical components of this architecture,
- taught other programmers about event-driven architecture; did many code reviews.

waytomaster.com

Way To Master: Language Learning Platform

Founder, Lead Programmer

June 2014–Jan 2016

This was an after-hours project that was a part of bachelor's degree thesis. It makes easies to learn English through subtitles for movies. I've made it with two friends. Few months after graduation, we published a working application on a web gaining over 3000 unique registrations. The project also was on the front page of wykop.pl site (similar to reddit.com in Poland). Technology stack: C#, .NET, Asp.NET MVC, AntIr4, PostgreSQL. During the time of development, I:

- managed a team of three people (including myself),
- created the architecture of the whole system (sort of Domain Driven Design),
- implemented efficient parsers and compilers for subtitles (this part is on my Github account),
- implemented a prototype of a desktop application (C++/Qt/QML, available for download),
- configured Continuous Integration environment (Jenkins, MSBuild, MSDeploy),
- created few views (AngularJS) and related backend code (ASP.NET MVC).

Currently, the project is unmaintained; some parts are available on my GitHub account, others are also available for review but not publicly available.

LGBS Polska Sp. z o.o.

Internal HR Applications September 2013–April 2015

C# Programmer

I was a member of a team responsible for creating internal web applications for the automation of HR processes within the company. Technology stack: Asp.NET MVC, KnockoutJS, C#, SQL Server. I was doing full-stack development including:

- modeling and implementing business logic (Domain Driven Design),
- squashing a lot of bugs and optimizing parts of the system,
- talking to end-users of the system and planning next tasks.

LGBS Polska Sp. z o.o.

C# Programmer

January 2012-September 2013

At the beginning of my professional career, I was working on different small projects. My activities mostly consisted of fixing bugs and implementing components for existing systems on my own. From September 2012 to September 2013 I was developing an ArcGIS-based desktop solution. Starting in April 2013, I regularly conduct technical interviews with new people who want to join the company. In 2014, I was also doing internal technical training sessions for new developers.

Education

Master of Computer Science
Silesian University of Technology

2013-2016

Bachelor of Computer Science
Silesian University of Technology

2009-2013

Selected skills

- Very strong: C#, .NET, Domain Driven Design, Object Oriented Programming, application design, microservices modeling.
- Strong: Linux, Windows, Entity Framework, SQL, UX Design, agile methodologies in practice, showing ideas by drawing diagrams.
- o Familiar: Haskell, C, Elastic Search, Kafka.

Interests and extra-curricular activity

- o I play on a clarinet in a local folk band (Zespół Pieśni i Tańca Chorzów) and two orchestras (Chorzowska Orkiestra Miejska and Chorzowska Orkiestra Kameralna Per Tutti). I'm an instrumentalist, I graduated from Grzegorz Fitelberg's High Music School in Chorzów. Besides that, I enjoy playing software synthesizers and piano.
- o I like to write during high school I've cooperated with Linux+ and Twoja Muza magazines creating over a dozen publications on a variety of topics (in polish, available on-demand on a paper). In my current project, I'm one of the people who enjoy writing clear documentation.
- o I like doing MOOC's. The first one was *Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, University of Stanford*) in 2011 and since then I did a lot of different courses. Some of them are related to my professional career (like *Software Security, University of Maryland* or *Data Analysis, John Hopkins University*), some other are just food for thought (like *Introduction To Astronomy, Duke University*). It's awesome that today anyone with computer and connection to the Internet, from whatever place, can learn from top quality materials virtually at no cost.